Love. Expulsion. Revolution.
Rushmore is a comedy, drama film directed by Wes Anderson.
When a beautiful first-grade teacher arrives at a prep school, she soon attracts the
attention of an ambitious teenager named Max, who quickly falls in love with her.
Max turns to the father of two of his schoolmates
for advice on how to woo the teacher.
However, the situation soon gets complicated when Max's new friend becomes involved with
her, setting the two pals against one another in a war for her attention.
Max Fischer, played by Jason Schwartzman.
Herman Blume, played by Bill Murray.
Rosemary Cross, played by Olivia Williams.
Bert Fischer, played by Seymour Cassel.
Dr. Nelson Guggenheim, played by Brian Cox.
Dirk Calloway, played by Mason Gamble.
Rushmore is a 1998 American comedy film  directed by Wes Anderson about a teenager named Max Fischer (Jason Schwartzman in his film debut), his friendship
with rich industrialist Herman Blume (Bill Murray), and their shared affection for elementary school teacher Rosemary Cross (Olivia Williams).
The film was co-written by Anderson and Owen Wilson.
The soundtrack features multiple songs by bands associated
with the British Invasion of the 1960s.
Filming began in November 1997 around Houston, Texas, and
lasted 50 days, until late January 1998.
While the box office results were modest, the film had a
positive reception among film critics.
The film helped launch Schwartzman's career while establishing a "second
career" for Murray as a respected actor in independent cinema.
At the 1999 Independent Spirit Awards, Anderson won the Best
Director award and Murray won Best Supporting Male award.
Murray also earned a nomination for the Golden Globe Award
for Best Supporting Actor – Motion Picture.
Starting from Rushmore, both Murray and Schwartzman became
two of Anderson's most frequent collaborators.
They have appeared in ten and seven subsequent films, respectively.
The film was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the Library of
Congress in 2016, deemed "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant".
The film explores themes of lone wolf, private school,
theater play, theatre group, theater director.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional and thought_provoking.